<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Festivals | GrooveUnion]]></title>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/categories/festivals/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-09T15:17:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Be Back Monday]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/be-back-monday/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T12:46:46-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/be-back-monday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://www.inthestands.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/be-back-soon.jpg">http://www.inthestands.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/be-back-soon.jpg</a>" width="250" height="225" title="be back soon #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>The GrooveUnion team will be at Summer Camp Music Festival this weekend!  We will be back on Monday with updates from the festival.  We hope to see all you happy people there!</p>

<p>Groove On&hellip;</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3SwFSAGPgWw " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer Camp Music Festival: 2008 vs. 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/21/summercamp-music-festival-2008-vs-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-21T13:10:19-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/21/summercamp-music-festival-2008-vs-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/scamp.jpg" width="150" height="225" title="scamp #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>As an avid festival goer for the past decade, I can say with confidence that Summer Camp Music Festival is the place to be this year. With its best lineup ever, latest daily band schedule with the main stages playing until 2AM, and longest band list to date, you do not want to miss it! Summer Camp Music Festival is a 3-day festival held every year over Memorial weekend in Chillicothe, IL (just outside of Peoria). Summer Camp began in 2001 with a bill of only 11 bands. In its 14th year, the festival will host more than 125 bands next month. Last week, Rolling Stone magazine even named Summer Camp as one of the “Summer 2014’s 40 Must-See Music Festivals”.</p>

<p>This writer has been to more than 10 different festivals across the county, and will be attending my 7th Summer Camp this year with my first having been in 2008. Instead of writing a post talking about how many amazing bands are going to be there and who they are, this post is intended to shed light on the changes that Summer Camp has made in the past 7 years to make this one of the premiere festivals in the country. Besides, a lineup including 3 nights of Moe., 3 nights of Umphrey’s Mcgee, 2 sets of Trey Anastasio Band, Primus, G. Love &amp; Special Sauce, Blues Traveler, The Wood Brothers, Yonder Mountain String Band, and Keller Williams should pretty much speak for itself in my humble opinion.</p>

<p>There have been so many positive changes to the festival since 2008 that the first or second-time Summer Camp goer would have no clue about! This is one of the only festivals in the country that listen to the feedback from people that attend the festival and actually make the desired changes. Don’t get me wrong, there are still some major changes in my opinion that would help the festival tremendously. However, the changes that have been made since 2008 have helped the festival in more ways than I could have hoped to imagine.</p>

<p>The biggest difference that has helped Summer Camp become more “user-friendly” is the set up at the festival entrance. My first year in 2008, we went on the Thursday for the Pre-Party and sat in line for at least 4-5 hours before even getting inside the festival (after we had already parked). It was one, giant line that wrapped all the way around into the parking lot. The security check, wristbands, late night tickets, EVERYTHING was all in ONE single line all while baking in the hot sun with fully loaded wagons, carts, arms, bags, backpacks, etc. It was a nightmare to say the least. By the time we got through the line, half the day was already over. Now, flash-forward to 2014. There’s a separate pod for your tickets before you get in the line, along with a handful of lanes at the security checkpoint instead of just one. It has saved hours upon hours of waiting time at the entrance and is so much more fluid.</p>

<p>The next big thing that helped was a very subtle change that most people probably thought was no big deal. For the first five years I attended Summer Camp, there was only one way in and one way out of the main stage at the festival off to the side (Moonshine). Last year, they created a big hole/path in the back of Moonshine Stage so that you can walk straight through the back which gives a direct line to the other main stage (Sunshine). And for people like me, this was huge because our campsite was between Moonshine and Sunshine right behind the Moonshine stage behind this newly created path.</p>

<p>The last major difference I’d like to bring up is one that rookie Summer Campers may have no clue about. The location of Sunshine stage has been in a new location the past two years in comparison to years past. The location of where Sunshine used to be is now more area for camping. They moved the stage further out in a parallel fashion to expand the boundaries of the festival which has helped tremendously for this growing festival. Moving the stage allowed for more people to attend the festival, it is not as cramped in the camping area, and it has created more standing room for the stages.</p>

<p>What am I most excited for this year at Summer Camp in my 7th year that will be different from the rest of the years I have attended? THE SCHEDULE! Two of the most heartbreaking things about Summer Camp in the past have been the main stages only playing until 10 or 11PM each year and how you have to have additional tickets for the late night shows in the red barn which always end up being headlining acts like Umphrey’s Mcgee and Moe. I will be going down a new path this year at Summer Camp by finally springing for VIP tickets. There are a lot of perks that make VIP worthwhile that I could get into, but possibly my favorite perk is my choice of one late night ticket in the red barn. I have tried the past 6 years to see a show in the barn, but only got lucky enough to get into only one show. This year, I have my late night ticket and am ready to go. As for the schedule, the main stages will be going until 2AM this year, which will make Summer Camp even better and I did not think that was possible.</p>

<p>Now if we can just get the folks that put on Summer Camp to pave the parking lots as well as keep all the torrential rain away that have dampened (literally) 3 of my last 6 Summer Camps, then this festival would be absolutely perfect. Don’t get me wrong, every time it has rained I have still had the time of my life. But, it did take my girlfriend some talking into for this year. It took me seven years, but this year I will be ready for the rain. I will be ready with my rain suit and men’s rain boots (yes that’s a real thing).</p>

<p>The GrooveUnion squad will all be in attendance next weekend for Summer Camp, and we will be reporting back to our readers about the best moments, sets, bands, and experiences that we have this year at the best festival on the planet! Stay tuned, and stay groovy.</p>

<p>LINK FOR SUMMERCAMP PAGE: <a href="http://summercampfestival.com/">http://summercampfestival.com/</a></p>

<p>Spotify Playlist: <a href="https://play.spotify.com/user/summercampfest/playlist/0Dg70qPImUry6QILrrm9Or">https://play.spotify.com/user/summercampfest/playlist/0Dg70qPImUry6QILrrm9Or</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riot Fest Suprise]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/riotfest10albums/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-16T23:32:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/riotfest10albums</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/riotfest.jpg" width="250" height="200" title="riot2" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>To commemorate its 10th anniversary, Riot Fest has announced that 10 bands will perform classic albums in full at the festival.  Among the participating bands:</p>

<ul>
<li>Weezer (The Blue Album)</li>
<li>Janes Addiction (Nothing&rsquo;s shocking)</li>
<li>Descendents (Milo Goes to College)</li>
<li>The Get Up Kids (Something to Write Home About)</li>
<li>Slayer (Reign in Blood)</li>
<li>The Offspring ( Smash)</li>
<li>NOFX (Punk in Drublic)</li>
<li>Samhain (Initium)</li>
<li>Naked Raygun (Throb Throb)</li>
</ul>


<p>The 10th and final band to play an album in full is yet to be announced.  &ldquo;We have promised to unveil it in a separate announcement in the upcoming weeks, as well as additional 10th anniversary surprises.&rdquo;  Click &ldquo;here&rdquo; to see Riot Fest dates and schedule.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FYF Fest Lineup]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/fsffestivallineup/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-16T23:31:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/fsffestivallineup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/fyffest.jpg" width="185" height="200" title="fyf" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>FYF Fest has revealed its 2014 lineup.  The Los Angeles-based music festival will take place August 23rd-24th at LA Sports Arena and Exposition Park.  The Strokes and Phoenix will serve as the two headlining acts, with other notable acts including Interpol, Flying Lotus, Blood Brother, Julian Casablancas and many others.  Check out the full lineup here:  <a href="http://fyffest.com">http://fyffest.com</a></p>

<p>Tickets will be available Thursday, May 22nd at Noon PST via the festival&rsquo;s website, and two day general admission passes will cost $129.00.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lollapalooza Releases Schedule]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/15/lollapalooza/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-15T12:09:01-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/15/lollapalooza</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/lolla.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Category:Lollapalooza_2014#mediaviewer/File:LOLAPALOOZA_2014.jpg">Photo</a> by Leonardo Levatti/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">CC By 3.0</a>
</div>




<br/ >


<br/ >


<p>Lollapalooza has released its schedule for its 2014 festival.  The festival takes place August 1st-3rd at Chicago&rsquo;s Grant Park.  Festival headliners include: Outkast, Eminem, Arctic Monkeys, Kings of Leon, Cage the Elephant, The Avett Brothers, Skrillex, Calvin Harris, Chromeo, among others.</p>

<p>Check out the full day-by-day schedule at: <a href="http://www.lollapalooza.com/2014-schedule/">http://www.lollapalooza.com/2014-schedule/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
