<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-17T18:54:15-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/17/songoftheday/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-17T18:08:40-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/17/songoftheday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/songdayimage.jpg" width="205" height="225" title="songoftheday #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/kxlJ5nEowCM " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Song: Bird in a House &ndash; Railroad Earth</p>

<br />


<p>Send us your song of the day at <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x67;&#114;&#111;&#111;&#118;&#101;&#117;&#110;&#105;&#111;&#x6e;&#x40;&#x6f;&#x75;&#116;&#108;&#111;&#x6f;&#107;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;">&#103;&#x72;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#118;&#101;&#x75;&#110;&#105;&#x6f;&#110;&#64;&#x6f;&#x75;&#116;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#111;&#x6b;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Avett Brothers Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/02/the-avett-bros-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T14:05:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/02/the-avett-bros-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/avettbros.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Avett_Brothers,_Pickathon_2006.jpg">Photo</a> by David Owen/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en">CC By 3.0</a>


<br/ >
<br/ >
<br/ >

The Avett Brothers
<br/ >
6/14/2014
<br/ >
The Lawn at White River State Park
<br/ >
Support: Langhorne Slim & the Law

</div>




<br/ >


<p>It is hard to find a more entertaining show out there than the Avett Brothers. Their stage presence is undeniable and has your heart racing from the first beat to the last beat. Whether they are stomping on the stage or hopping around, they will leave you wanting more. This was not the first time I have seen the Avett Brothers at White River, but I must say I enjoyed this year’s show compared to last time there three years ago. However, this was mostly due to the show being outdoors in the middle of October. I had trouble enjoying the show because I was struggling to keep myself warm the entire show.</p>

<p>This time around, I could not have asked for better weather. It was perfect outside, and they killed it with a twenty-four song set list. They started out strong with some well-known songs like ‘Live and Die’ and ‘Pretty Girl from Cedar Lane’ before settling down with songs like ‘Vanity’ and ‘Laundry Room’. Right after ‘Vanity’, they busted out my personal favorite ‘Kick Drum Heart’ which had the crowd back up and dancing after a few slow ones.</p>

<p>One thing I do remember about the show a few years ago were the uniquely chosen covers like Neutral Milk Hotel’s ‘In the Aeroplane Over the Sea’. No Neutral Milk Hotel this time, but they did however cover a pretty fun George Jones song called ‘The Race Is On’. I had not heard this one before, but I liked it. The same could be said about the first song of the encore which was a Doc Watson cover called ‘Little Sadie’.  They closed the show out with the crowd favorite and ever-popular ‘I and Love and You’. This was the same song they closed with last time I saw them, and I would not have had it any other way this time around. It is such a pretty melodic song with outstanding lyrics that had the whole crowd singing along.</p>

<p>I do not know the Avett Brothers catalog as well as a lot of other bands I listen to, but they always put on an incredible show. With unmatched energy and a style that hits a few different musical genres, they are able to keep the set lists fresh and exciting. This concert-goer will be 100% going back to see the Avett Brothers next time they are in Indiana.</p>

<p>SETLIST: <a href="http://www.setlist.fm/setlist/the-avett-brothers/2014/farm-bureau-insurance-lawn-at-white-river-state-park-indianapolis-in-6bc07e72.html">http://www.setlist.fm/setlist/the-avett-brothers/2014/farm-bureau-insurance-lawn-at-white-river-state-park-indianapolis-in-6bc07e72.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[John Butler Trio Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/02/john-butler-trio-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T12:13:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/02/john-butler-trio-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/JBT.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4f/Bonnaroo08_jackjohnson2_lg.jpg">Photo</a> by Nigel Cooke/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en">CC By 2.0</a>


<br/ >
<br/ >
<br/ >

John Butler Trio Review
<br/ >
6/12/2014
<br/ >
Egyptian Room at Old National Centre

</div>




<br/ >


<p>John Butler Trio has been hitting the road hard in support of their most recent album, Flesh &amp; Blood. The GrooveUnion crew and I caught their show at the Egyptian Room at Old National Centre in Indianapolis, and wow what an entertaining show. They played all the hits you could hope for with their new songs perfectly mixed in to the set.</p>

<p>Not to take away from the show, but I remember seeing him at the Egyptian Room in 2008 and his look and energy was definitely different in 2014. In 2008, he was hopping and dancing around the stage the entire time like you see Michael Franti do at his shows. Also in 2008 John had long dreads, baggy hippy pants, and a hippy t-shirt. Flash forward to 2014, John was a little different. He was dressed very nice with a clean-cut, perm-like hair-cut. Not to mention, he stayed somewhat stationary the entire show not really dancing and hopping around. When I noticed the changes as he came on stage and started playing, I was a little reserved as to how the show would unfold in comparison to 2008. John put all those worries to rest quickly with his unbelievable show. This show was just as good, if not better, than the show in 2008.</p>

<p>The band started out nice and calm with their new song ‘Cold Wind’, before ripping into old songs ‘Revolution’ and ‘Used to Get High’ and they never looked back! You could feel the vibe of the crowd intensifying as they killed it with ‘Used to Get High’. There was everyone from teenagers to senior citizens getting down and dancing through the set.  There was one specific senior citizen lady that seemed to be one of his biggest fans close to us that was dancing like a teenager the entire show. It was very entertaining for us throughout the show.</p>

<p>As the band continued through their nineteen song set, they continued to place new songs in like ‘Bullet Girl’, ‘Only One’, ‘Blame It On Me’, ‘Devil Woman’, ‘How You Sleep at Night’, and ‘Livin’ in the City’. All in all, they played 7 of the 11 new tracks from Flesh &amp; Blood and I was not upset. Usually when I see a band touring in support of a new album, I always am hoping they will stick to their old songs. With the new Flesh &amp; Blood, that was not the case with John Butler. I love the new CD, and loved hearing them live.</p>

<p>For the GrooveUnion crew and I, there was one song that we were all hoping for in the back of our heads and is obviously ‘Ocean’. After about half of the set was complete, John was on stage alone and busted into ‘Ocean’ and it is just utterly amazing. I have been to a countless number of concerts, and hearing ‘Ocean’ live by John Butler is still hard to beat. It is one of the most awe-struck moments you could ever have at a concert. It just puts you in a trance from the first note to the last note and he could not have played it any more perfect.</p>

<p>John Butler Trio is one of those shows that is pretty much impossible not to leave in a better mood than when you arrived. He is such a happy, uplifting performer that I would see again and again. It is amazing that he still makes stops in places like Indianapolis all the way from Australia while still playing all his hits for his fans that we know and love. One thing is for sure John, you are always welcome back and we will be there when you come.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/11/songoftheday/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-11T14:29:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/11/songoftheday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/songdayimage.jpg" width="205" height="225" title="songoftheday #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4cGphy7XeZk " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Song: Mary Had a Little Lamb &ndash; Stevie Ray Vaughan</p>

<br />


<p>Send us your song of the day at <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#58;&#103;&#x72;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#118;&#101;&#x75;&#110;&#105;&#x6f;&#110;&#x40;&#x6f;&#x75;&#116;&#108;&#x6f;&#111;&#x6b;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;">&#x67;&#114;&#x6f;&#111;&#118;&#x65;&#117;&#110;&#105;&#x6f;&#x6e;&#x40;&#111;&#x75;&#116;&#108;&#x6f;&#111;&#107;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch: Jack White Live In Concert Webcast]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/11/jack-white-free-webcast-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-11T14:08:27-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/11/jack-white-free-webcast-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/white.jpg" width="220" height="225" title="White Webcast" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>On Monday night (June 9) Jack White celebrated the release of his latest solo album, <em>Lazaretto</em>, with a live concert and webcast from the historic Fonda Theater in Hollywood, Calif.  The show started out with White playing many songs from the new album and lead into a mix of old White Stripes classics.</p>

<p>Please, if you have the two and a half hours, click the link below and watch the full webcast of the show.  White was in an energetic and talkative mood.  The energy was on full blast all night, and the setlist was carefully crafted with mind numbing jams sparsed inbetween.  Even though I am occasionally put off by White&rsquo;s high pitched guitar style, it really sets the tone for the band and the crowds enthusiasm.  His solos are so well placed you habitually get lost in its psychedelic tendencies.</p>

<p>White is a songwriting genius who hasn&rsquo;t lost a step since his White Stripes days.  He seems to be having as much fun as ever and should be on every music fans bucket list.  His energy, stage presence, and originality are unmatched in the industry today.</p>

<p>P.S. What the hell is the instrument the lap steel guitar player is playing in the middle of the show?</p>

<p>Live Webcast link:  <a href="http://www.npr.org/event/music/319666614/live-tuesday-jack-white-in-concert">http://www.npr.org/event/music/319666614/live-tuesday-jack-white-in-concert</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lionel Richie Goes Country]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/07/lionel-richie-goes-country/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-07T20:09:55-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/07/lionel-richie-goes-country</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/lionel.jpg" width="175" height="225" title="Jay z" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href=”https://www.flickr.com/photos/rockcousteau/9810268054/in/photolist-9ta1jM-3Bvvu5-9oyMqz-aqAcK7-fWUbUE-aQghLz-aQgi5t-aQghTr-aQghBX-aQghsv-aQgbgD-aQge1P-aQg9Yp-aQg7hF-aQgfbc-yS9Bp-nqWJQY-sxfcp-8w7Jm6-86juWe-rcQWL-86juxH-7cgyvk-86juap-NoNYk-971yUw-dLGB8V-86nEhd-86Tksi-86nDNY-86TmtH-86jw6n-86TnhV-86jvUT-axrVMB-86jvt6-9ESb1X-6mHXTi-aiJpGA-9prA5w-6mHXLp-6mHXNF-6mN8Dm-6mN6Nu-58MWTN-86nF9b-86jvgB-86Wxsy-86TmGR-86WxMS”>Photo</a>  by Rock Cousteau/ <a href=”https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/”>CC by 2.0 </a>
</div>


<p></p>

<br/ >


<br/ > 


<p>Via <a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/music/news/lionel-richie-promises-country-sequel-20140606">Rolling Stone</a>, Lionel Richie promises his next album will be country.  “It&rsquo;s coming,” he told Rolling Stone backstage at Wednesday&rsquo;s CMT Awards.  The planning for the country album has been going on since the making of &lsquo;Tuskegee&rsquo;, in which he sang numerous duets with some of country&rsquo;s biggest stars (Blake Shelton, Shania Twain, Kenny Chesney, Willie Nelson).</p>

<p>&ldquo;You cannot not be inspired,&rdquo; he said of joining the country music scene. &ldquo;What I&rsquo;m missing in the pop world and in the R&amp;B world are great songs. And whether I want to admit it or not, country&rsquo;s writing songs that are sticking around for the next 400 years. They&rsquo;re writing music. And so, this is my heaven. When my record company came back and said, &lsquo;Would you consider another one? How do you feel about country?&rsquo; I said, &lsquo;Well it&rsquo;s pop music to me.&rsquo;  So I&rsquo;m going to stay around here for a while. I love all of my new friends. My &lsquo;brand new old friends,&rsquo; as I call them.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Tweedy show]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/07/first-tweedy-show/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-07T20:09:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/07/first-tweedy-show</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/tweedy.jpg" width="110" height="205" title="Jay z" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href=”http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Jeff_Tweedy.jpg”>Photo</a>  by Larry Philpot/ <a href=”http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en”>CC By 3.0 </a>
</div>


<p></p>

<br/ >


<br/ > 


<p>The new band <em>Tweedy</em>, comprised of the father-son duo of Spencer and Jeff Tweedy, played their first show together on Thursday night.  As <a href="http://consequenceofsound.net/2014/06/jeff-and-spencer-tweedy-play-first-show-as-tweedy/">Consequence of Sound</a> states, Tweedy played a 13-song set full of material from their upcoming album, Sukierae.  After, Jeff played a solo set before Tweedy returned for the encore.</p>

<p>Setlist:</p>

<ul>
<li>Down From Above</li>
<li>Flowering</li>
<li>Summer Noon</li>
<li>World Away</li>
<li>New Moon</li>
<li>Where My Love</li>
<li>Slow Love</li>
<li>Nobody Dies</li>
<li>Honey Combed</li>
<li>Desert Bell</li>
<li>High as hello</li>
<li>Wait For Love</li>
<li>Low Key</li>
</ul>


<p>Solo:</p>

<ul>
<li>Spiders</li>
<li>Passenger Side</li>
<li>You Are Not Alone</li>
<li>The Ruling Class</li>
<li>New Madrid</li>
<li>Kicking Television</li>
<li>I Am Trying to Break Your Heart</li>
<li>Jesus Etc.</li>
<li>Misunderstood</li>
</ul>


<p>Encore:</p>

<ul>
<li>Diamond Love</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m the Man Who Loves You</li>
<li>Acuff-Rose</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jack Johnson Concert Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/06/jackjohnsonreview/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-06T13:34:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/06/jackjohnsonreview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/jackjohnson.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4f/Bonnaroo08_jackjohnson2_lg.jpg">Photo</a> by Josh Rhinehart/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en">CC By 3.0</a>


<br/ >
<br/ >
<br/ >

JACK JOHNSON CONCERT REVIEW
<br/ >
6/1/2014 The Lawn at White River State Park
<br/ >
Support: Amos Lee

</div>




<br/ >


<p>Anybody that lives in Indiana knows that you never know what the weather could be like at any given hour at a time. Last night, the Jack Johnson concert on the Lawn at White River State Park proved this point even further. Yesterday started as a beautiful day only for the weathermen to announce late in the day that severe weather was coming and was going to hit hard until about 8:45PM. The opener, Amos Lee, came on and played about three songs before they kicked him off the stage and urged everyone to exit the venue and seek shelter at approximately 7:45. It was barely drizzling and partly cloudy with a handful of lightning bolts. However, the masses started the mass exodus to neighboring buildings to catch a few drinks before heading back to the Lawn and catch Jack’s set which the venue stated they were sure would still happen.</p>

<p>Well, the rain never came and everyone started pouring back into the venue about 20-30 minutes after the announcement was made telling everyone to leave. It never did end up raining, ended up feeling perfect outside, and Jack still played an entire two-hour set beginning at 9PM that covered everything from his first album to his newest album along with some excellent covers.</p>

<p>I have seen Jack multiple times, and every time I get worried Jack is going to stick to new material during his set and steer away from his older hits that made me fall in love with Jack originally. This was definitely not the case. He had a perfect balance of old hits, new hits, and covers nicely placed throughout the set. It also was amazing that his band supporting him was members of ALO (Animal Liberation Orchestra), who is also a band on the same label as Jack. They added an extra something to the show that would not have been the same without them.</p>

<p>Most people get the impression that a Jack Johnson show would be a boring, quiet show that is not very upbeat. Jack kept the crowd into it the entire time and was even listening and playing requests that were screamed out from the crowd! Not only that, he even played a song the crowd was screaming for all night that was actually an ALO song. It is nice when a popular musician like Jack can put his ego aside and give the fans what they want, and Jack was definitely showing this side of him to his fans last night and you could tell the crowd loved it.</p>

<p>It was a bummer to a lot of Amos Lee fans in attendance that his set got cut short. However, Jack made right by bringing him and his band on stage multiple times to play with him along with 2 or 3 songs in the encore. To end the show, Jack had the members from ALO, Amos Lee and his band, and himself on stage to close the set. There were a lot of people on stage at that moment, but it was amazing how fluent and great they all sounded together like they had been doing it for years!</p>

<p>A Jack Johnson concert is never going to be the best concert you have ever seen, nor will it ever be the worst concert you have ever seen. But it has always entertained me in a big way and I leave happy and satisfied every time. Jack has never changed his musical style unlike many artists today, and he should be commended for that. I saw Jack about 8 years ago, again about 4 years ago, and now last night. It has gotten better and better each time, and I will continue to go see him as long as he continues to tour!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/06/songoftheday/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-06T13:28:31-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/06/songoftheday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/songdayimage.jpg" width="205" height="225" title="songoftheday #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2fXKNwo5ik8 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Song: Groundhog&rsquo;s Day &ndash; Primus</p>

<br />


<p>Send us your song of the day at <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#108;&#116;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#x67;&#x72;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#x76;&#101;&#117;&#x6e;&#105;&#x6f;&#110;&#x40;&#111;&#117;&#x74;&#108;&#x6f;&#111;&#107;&#x2e;&#x63;&#111;&#109;">&#x67;&#x72;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#x76;&#x65;&#117;&#110;&#105;&#x6f;&#x6e;&#64;&#x6f;&#x75;&#116;&#108;&#111;&#x6f;&#x6b;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Killed Off Game of Thrones]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/06/get-killed-off-game-of-thrones/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-06T00:09:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/06/get-killed-off-game-of-thrones</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/georgerrmartin.jpg" width="140" height="225" title="george" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href=”http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:George_R.R._Martin_by_Gage_Skidmore.jpg”>Photo</a>  by Gage Skidmore/ <a href=”http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en”>CC by 3.0 </a>
</div>




<br/ >


<br/ > 


<p>Via <a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/george-rr-martin-contest-winner-709769">The Hollywood Reporter</a>, for a mere $20,000 you can be wrote in and killed off of <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> by George RR Martin.  The $20,000 is raising funds for Santa Fe&rsquo;s Wild Spirit Wolf Sanctuary, along with the local Food Depot of Santa Fe.  There will be one male and one female wrote in and subsequently killed off, and they are each allowed to choose their characters class in the world (lord, knight, peasant, whore, lady, maester, septon, etc.)</p>

<p>For the not-so-rich, other prizes include eating breakfast with Martin himself ($15,000), attending the TV series&#8217; Season 5 premiere ($7,500), and basically buying one of Martin&rsquo;s signature hats for $7,500.  The fundraiser was developed by Martin and his wife, Parris McBride.</p>

<p>Who would&rsquo;ve thought Martin and his wife would be into wolves?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Petty-American Dream Plan B]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/05/tom-petty-american-dream-plan-b/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-05T00:09:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/05/tom-petty-american-dream-plan-b</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/petty.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="Jay z" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href=”http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:George_R.R._Martin_by_Gage_Skidmore.jpg”>Photo </a>  by Gage Skidmore/ <a href=”http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en”>CC by 3.0  </a >
</div>




<br/ >


<br/ > 


<p>Tom Petty and the Heartbreakers have released their first single, <strong>American Dream Plan B</strong> from their forthcoming album, <em>Hypnotic Eye</em>.  Petty calls the record &ldquo;a straight hard-rockin&#8217; record, from beginning to end.”  &lsquo;American Dream Plan B&rsquo; confirms that notion and gets this writer very excited about the upcoming album.</p>

<p>listen to the stream on soundcloud via <a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/music/news/hear-tom-pettys-old-school-rocker-american-dream-plan-b-premiere-20140605">Rolling Stone</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Strokes First Show in 3 Years]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/01/the-strokes-first-show-in-3-years/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-01T11:16:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/01/the-strokes-first-show-in-3-years</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/thestrokes.jpg" width="150" height="225" title="casablanca" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/59272703@N00/256950941/">Photo</a> by nica/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/">CC By 2.0</a>
</div>




<br/ >


<br/ >


<p>The Strokes played a live concert for the first time in almost three years last night (May 31).  The band played what seemed to be a warm-up show for their upcoming set at Governor&rsquo;s Ball Music Festival.</p>

<p>Setlist:</p>

<ul>
<li>Barely Legal</li>
<li>Welcome to Japan (Live debut)</li>
<li>Automatic Stop</li>
<li>Machu Picchu</li>
<li>Reptilia</li>
<li>Razorblade</li>
<li>Take It or Leave It</li>
<li><p>One Way Trigger (Live debut)</p></li>
<li><p>Under Control</p></li>
<li>Heart in a Cage</li>
<li>Hard to Explain</li>
<li>12:51</li>
<li>Someday</li>
<li>Happy Ending (Live debut)</li>
<li>The End Has No End</li>
<li>You Only Live Once</li>
<li>Last Nite</li>
<li>New York City Cops</li>
</ul>


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6O7SbpTzc1c " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince is Awesome]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/31/princeisawesome/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-31T11:16:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/31/princeisawesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/princeatcoachella.jpg" width="230" height="225" title="guitar" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/penner/2450784866">Photo</a> by Scott Penner/ <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/">CC By 2.0</a>
</div>




<br/ >


<br/ >


<p>Last night, Prince performed three shows in the span of five hours for a small club of people in Brussles, Belgium.  Prince has been known to put on unique performances and continues to suprise and thrill fans.  Every performance and special show Prince does proves how much he truly loves playing music.</p>

<p>(My favorite Prince moment.  I love when he just tosses the guitar up when he&rsquo;s done.  who catches it? Did it ever land?)</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6SFNW5F8K9Y " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Show 1 Setlist:</p>

<ul>
<li>Endorphinmachine</li>
<li>Screwdriver</li>
<li>She’s Always in My Hair</li>
<li>Guitar</li>
<li>Take Me With U</li>
<li>Raspberry Beret</li>
<li>U Got the Look</li>
<li>Musicology</li>
<li>Kiss</li>
<li>When Doves Cry</li>
<li>Alphabet St.</li>
</ul>


<p>Encore:</p>

<ul>
<li>Purple Rain</li>
</ul>


<p>Show 2 Setlist:</p>

<ul>
<li>Funknroll</li>
<li>Controversy</li>
<li>Little Red Corvette</li>
<li>Nothing Compares 2 U (The Family cover)</li>
<li>Let’s Go Crazy</li>
<li>Take Me With U</li>
<li>Raspberry Beret</li>
<li>U Got the Look</li>
<li>Cool (The Time cover)</li>
<li>Live it Up pt 1 &amp; 2 (The Isley Brothers cover)</li>
<li>Kiss</li>
</ul>


<p>Show 3 Setlist:</p>

<ul>
<li>Plectrum Electrum</li>
<li>FixUrLifeUp</li>
<li>Something in the Water (Does Not Compute)</li>
<li>Empty Room</li>
<li>Pretzelbodylogic</li>
<li>Stratus (Billy Cobham cover)</li>
<li>What’s My Name? (with the lyrics to The Sacrifice of Victor)</li>
<li>Musicology (incl. Mama Feelgood)</li>
<li>Kiss</li>
<li>Hot Thing</li>
<li>Nasty Girl (Vanity 6 cover)</li>
<li>Sign “☮” the Times</li>
<li>Housequake</li>
<li>I Would Die 4 U</li>
</ul>


<p>Encore:</p>

<ul>
<li>Purple Rain</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[White Rips Black Keys]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/29/white-rips-black-keys/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-29T11:16:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/29/white-rips-black-keys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/jackwhite.jpg" width="120" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Jack_White_Ottawa.jpg">Photo</a> by Scott Penner/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/">CC By 2.0</a>
</div>




<br/ >


<br/ >


<p>Jack White obviously does not like the black keys.  In a new interview with <a href="http://rollingstone.com/">Rolling Stone</a>, White did not have kind words for the 2-man “copycat” band, as White would claim. “There are kids at school who dress like everybody else, because they don’t know what to do, and there are musicians like that, too,” White said. “I’ll hear TV commercials where the music’s ripping off sounds of mine, to the point I think it’s me. Half the time, it’s The Black Keys. The other half, it’s a sound-alike song because they couldn’t license one of mine. There’s a whole world that’s totally fine with the watered-down version of the original.”</p>

<p>The no love lost relationship dates back to the summer of 2013 when TMZ released email exchanges between White and his wife Karen Elson.  “My concern with Auerbach is because I don’t want the kids involved in any of that crap. You aren’t thinking ahead. That’s a possible twelve fucking years I’m going to have to be sitting in kids chairs next to that asshole with other people trying to lump us in together. He gets yet another free reign to follow me around and copy me and push himself into my world.”</p>

<p>Jack White will not allow another two-piece band to steal any of the White Stripes former glory.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SummerCamp Brawl]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/26/summercamp-brawl/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-26T11:16:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/26/summercamp-brawl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/bottlesmash.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=770956559604195">Photo</a> by Jay Blakesberg 
</div>




<br/ >


<br/ >


<p>Summer Camp Music Festival started off all fun and games until things got heated backstage.  Here&rsquo;s the video of Moe.&rsquo;s Rob Derhak getting into a fight backstage with Umphrey&rsquo;s Mcgee&rsquo;s Ryan Stasik.</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Y46yNFc87YM " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Things continued to be all fun and games, even after the short melee.  We are way past April fools.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Be Back Monday]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/22/be-back-monday/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T12:46:46-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/22/be-back-monday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.inthestands.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/be-back-soon.jpg" width="250" height="225" title="be back soon #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>The GrooveUnion team will be at Summer Camp Music Festival this weekend!  We will be back on Monday with updates from the festival.  We hope to see all you happy people there!</p>

<p>Groove On&hellip;</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3SwFSAGPgWw " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Allman Sued]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/22/greg-allman-sued/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T12:36:39-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/22/greg-allman-sued</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/gregallman.jpg" width="250" height="225" title="bottle greg allman" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Allman_Brothers_Band_-_Gregg_Allman.jpg">Photo</a> by Carl Lender/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en">CC By 2.0</a>
</div>




<br/ >


<br/ >


<p>SAVANNAH, Ga.&ndash; Greg Allman is one of 18 parties being sued by the parents of a young camera assistant who died during the production of &ldquo;Midnight Rider,&rdquo; a movie based on Allman&rsquo;s memoir.  The crew was struck by a freight train in southeast Georgia.</p>

<p>The parents of 27-year old Sarah Jones filed a lawsuit that names 10 individuals associated with the film.  Including Allman, director Randall Miller, his production company, as well as CSX railroad.</p>

<p>“They did so many wrong things on so many levels, it’s just unbelievable,” Richard Jones said. “This should not have happened. It’s senseless.”  The lawsuit accuses all parties of negligence and seeks unspecified monetary damages.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/22/songoftheday/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T11:49:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/22/songoftheday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/songdayimage.jpg" width="205" height="225" title="songoftheday #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/soOfcwQ3J8A " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Summer Camp Music Festival today!</p>

<p>Song: Nebraska &ndash; Moe.</p>

<br />


<p>Send us your song of the day at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#58;&#x67;&#x72;&#111;&#111;&#x76;&#x65;&#x75;&#x6e;&#x69;&#111;&#x6e;&#x40;&#111;&#117;&#x74;&#108;&#111;&#x6f;&#x6b;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;">&#103;&#114;&#111;&#111;&#x76;&#x65;&#117;&#110;&#105;&#x6f;&#110;&#x40;&#111;&#117;&#116;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#111;&#107;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#109;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer Camp Music Festival: 2008 vs. 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/21/summercamp-music-festival-2008-vs-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-21T13:10:19-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/21/summercamp-music-festival-2008-vs-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/scamp.jpg" width="150" height="225" title="scamp #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>As an avid festival goer for the past decade, I can say with confidence that Summer Camp Music Festival is the place to be this year. With its best lineup ever, latest daily band schedule with the main stages playing until 2AM, and longest band list to date, you do not want to miss it! Summer Camp Music Festival is a 3-day festival held every year over Memorial weekend in Chillicothe, IL (just outside of Peoria). Summer Camp began in 2001 with a bill of only 11 bands. In its 14th year, the festival will host more than 125 bands next month. Last week, Rolling Stone magazine even named Summer Camp as one of the “Summer 2014’s 40 Must-See Music Festivals”.</p>

<p>This writer has been to more than 10 different festivals across the county, and will be attending my 7th Summer Camp this year with my first having been in 2008. Instead of writing a post talking about how many amazing bands are going to be there and who they are, this post is intended to shed light on the changes that Summer Camp has made in the past 7 years to make this one of the premiere festivals in the country. Besides, a lineup including 3 nights of Moe., 3 nights of Umphrey’s Mcgee, 2 sets of Trey Anastasio Band, Primus, G. Love &amp; Special Sauce, Blues Traveler, The Wood Brothers, Yonder Mountain String Band, and Keller Williams should pretty much speak for itself in my humble opinion.</p>

<p>There have been so many positive changes to the festival since 2008 that the first or second-time Summer Camp goer would have no clue about! This is one of the only festivals in the country that listen to the feedback from people that attend the festival and actually make the desired changes. Don’t get me wrong, there are still some major changes in my opinion that would help the festival tremendously. However, the changes that have been made since 2008 have helped the festival in more ways than I could have hoped to imagine.</p>

<p>The biggest difference that has helped Summer Camp become more “user-friendly” is the set up at the festival entrance. My first year in 2008, we went on the Thursday for the Pre-Party and sat in line for at least 4-5 hours before even getting inside the festival (after we had already parked). It was one, giant line that wrapped all the way around into the parking lot. The security check, wristbands, late night tickets, EVERYTHING was all in ONE single line all while baking in the hot sun with fully loaded wagons, carts, arms, bags, backpacks, etc. It was a nightmare to say the least. By the time we got through the line, half the day was already over. Now, flash-forward to 2014. There’s a separate pod for your tickets before you get in the line, along with a handful of lanes at the security checkpoint instead of just one. It has saved hours upon hours of waiting time at the entrance and is so much more fluid.</p>

<p>The next big thing that helped was a very subtle change that most people probably thought was no big deal. For the first five years I attended Summer Camp, there was only one way in and one way out of the main stage at the festival off to the side (Moonshine). Last year, they created a big hole/path in the back of Moonshine Stage so that you can walk straight through the back which gives a direct line to the other main stage (Sunshine). And for people like me, this was huge because our campsite was between Moonshine and Sunshine right behind the Moonshine stage behind this newly created path.</p>

<p>The last major difference I’d like to bring up is one that rookie Summer Campers may have no clue about. The location of Sunshine stage has been in a new location the past two years in comparison to years past. The location of where Sunshine used to be is now more area for camping. They moved the stage further out in a parallel fashion to expand the boundaries of the festival which has helped tremendously for this growing festival. Moving the stage allowed for more people to attend the festival, it is not as cramped in the camping area, and it has created more standing room for the stages.</p>

<p>What am I most excited for this year at Summer Camp in my 7th year that will be different from the rest of the years I have attended? THE SCHEDULE! Two of the most heartbreaking things about Summer Camp in the past have been the main stages only playing until 10 or 11PM each year and how you have to have additional tickets for the late night shows in the red barn which always end up being headlining acts like Umphrey’s Mcgee and Moe. I will be going down a new path this year at Summer Camp by finally springing for VIP tickets. There are a lot of perks that make VIP worthwhile that I could get into, but possibly my favorite perk is my choice of one late night ticket in the red barn. I have tried the past 6 years to see a show in the barn, but only got lucky enough to get into only one show. This year, I have my late night ticket and am ready to go. As for the schedule, the main stages will be going until 2AM this year, which will make Summer Camp even better and I did not think that was possible.</p>

<p>Now if we can just get the folks that put on Summer Camp to pave the parking lots as well as keep all the torrential rain away that have dampened (literally) 3 of my last 6 Summer Camps, then this festival would be absolutely perfect. Don’t get me wrong, every time it has rained I have still had the time of my life. But, it did take my girlfriend some talking into for this year. It took me seven years, but this year I will be ready for the rain. I will be ready with my rain suit and men’s rain boots (yes that’s a real thing).</p>

<p>The GrooveUnion squad will all be in attendance next weekend for Summer Camp, and we will be reporting back to our readers about the best moments, sets, bands, and experiences that we have this year at the best festival on the planet! Stay tuned, and stay groovy.</p>

<p>LINK FOR SUMMERCAMP PAGE: <a href="http://summercampfestival.com/">http://summercampfestival.com/</a></p>

<p>Spotify Playlist: <a href="https://play.spotify.com/user/summercampfest/playlist/0Dg70qPImUry6QILrrm9Or">https://play.spotify.com/user/summercampfest/playlist/0Dg70qPImUry6QILrrm9Or</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/21/songoftheday/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-21T12:21:01-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/05/21/songoftheday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.grooveunion.com/images/songdayimage.jpg" width="205" height="225" title="songoftheday #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/wRcVQDELAd4 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Song: Got to Give it Up &ndash; Marvin Gaye</p>

<br />


<p>Send us your song of the day at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#x3a;&#103;&#114;&#111;&#x6f;&#x76;&#x65;&#x75;&#110;&#x69;&#111;&#x6e;&#x40;&#111;&#117;&#x74;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#111;&#107;&#46;&#99;&#x6f;&#x6d;">&#x67;&#114;&#x6f;&#111;&#x76;&#101;&#117;&#110;&#x69;&#111;&#110;&#64;&#x6f;&#x75;&#x74;&#108;&#111;&#x6f;&#x6b;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x6d;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
