<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></title>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-02T15:37:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince is Awesome]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/31/princeisawesome/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-31T11:16:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/31/princeisawesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://proguitarshop.com/media/cms/blog/prince-purple-rain.jpg" width="170" height="225" title="Prince" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Last night, Prince performed three shows in the span of five hours for a small club of people in Brussles, Belgium.  Prince has been known to put on unique performances and continues to suprise and thrill fans.  Every performance and special show Prince does proves how much he truly loves playing music.</p>

<p>(My favorite Prince moment.  I love when he just tosses the guitar up when he&rsquo;s done.  who catches it? Did it ever land?)</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6SFNW5F8K9Y " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Show 1 Setlist:</p>

<ul>
<li>Endorphinmachine</li>
<li>Screwdriver</li>
<li>She’s Always in My Hair</li>
<li>Guitar</li>
<li>Take Me With U</li>
<li>Raspberry Beret</li>
<li>U Got the Look</li>
<li>Musicology</li>
<li>Kiss</li>
<li>When Doves Cry</li>
<li>Alphabet St.</li>
</ul>


<p>Encore:</p>

<ul>
<li>Purple Rain</li>
</ul>


<p>Show 2 Setlist:</p>

<ul>
<li>Funknroll</li>
<li>Controversy</li>
<li>Little Red Corvette</li>
<li>Nothing Compares 2 U (The Family cover)</li>
<li>Let’s Go Crazy</li>
<li>Take Me With U</li>
<li>Raspberry Beret</li>
<li>U Got the Look</li>
<li>Cool (The Time cover)</li>
<li>Live it Up pt 1 &amp; 2 (The Isley Brothers cover)</li>
<li>Kiss</li>
</ul>


<p>Show 3 Setlist:</p>

<ul>
<li>Plectrum Electrum</li>
<li>FixUrLifeUp</li>
<li>Something in the Water (Does Not Compute)</li>
<li>Empty Room</li>
<li>Pretzelbodylogic</li>
<li>Stratus (Billy Cobham cover)</li>
<li>What’s My Name? (with the lyrics to The Sacrifice of Victor)</li>
<li>Musicology (incl. Mama Feelgood)</li>
<li>Kiss</li>
<li>Hot Thing</li>
<li>Nasty Girl (Vanity 6 cover)</li>
<li>Sign “☮” the Times</li>
<li>Housequake</li>
<li>I Would Die 4 U</li>
</ul>


<p>Encore:</p>

<ul>
<li>Purple Rain</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[White Rips Black Keys]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/29/white-rips-black-keys/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-29T11:16:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/29/white-rips-black-keys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://assets-s3.rollingstone.com/assets/images/artists/304x304/jack-white.jpg" width="140" height="200" title="white" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Jack White obviously does not like the black keys.  In a new interview with <a href="http://rollingstone.com/">Rolling Stone</a>, White did not have kind words for the 2-man “copycat” band, as White would claim. “There are kids at school who dress like everybody else, because they don’t know what to do, and there are musicians like that, too,” White said. “I’ll hear TV commercials where the music’s ripping off sounds of mine, to the point I think it’s me. Half the time, it’s The Black Keys. The other half, it’s a sound-alike song because they couldn’t license one of mine. There’s a whole world that’s totally fine with the watered-down version of the original.”</p>

<p>The no love lost relationship dates back to the summer of 2013 when TMZ released email exchanges between White and his wife Karen Elson.  “My concern with Auerbach is because I don’t want the kids involved in any of that crap. You aren’t thinking ahead. That’s a possible twelve fucking years I’m going to have to be sitting in kids chairs next to that asshole with other people trying to lump us in together. He gets yet another free reign to follow me around and copy me and push himself into my world.”</p>

<p>Jack White will not allow another two-piece band to steal any of the White Stripes former glory.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SummerCamp Brawl]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/26/summercamp-brawl/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-26T11:16:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/26/summercamp-brawl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="https://scontent-a-ord.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpf1/t1.0-9/10376099_770956559604195_8365428609528047926_n.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Summer Camp Music Festival started off all fun and games until things got heated backstage.  Here&rsquo;s the video of Moe.&rsquo;s Rob Derhak getting into a fight backstage with Umphrey&rsquo;s Mcgee&rsquo;s Ryan Stasik.</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Y46yNFc87YM " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Things continued to be all fun and games, even after the short melee.  We are way past April fools.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Be Back Monday]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/be-back-monday/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T12:46:46-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/be-back-monday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.inthestands.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/be-back-soon.jpg" width="250" height="225" title="be back soon #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>The GrooveUnion team will be at Summer Camp Music Festival this weekend!  We will be back on Monday with updates from the festival.  We hope to see all you happy people there!</p>

<p>Groove On&hellip;</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3SwFSAGPgWw " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Allman Sued]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/greg-allman-sued/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T12:36:39-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/greg-allman-sued</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/13/Allman_Brothers_Band_-_Gregg_Allman.jpg" width="250" height="225" title="Greg Allman #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>SAVANNAH, Ga.&ndash; Greg Allman is one of 18 parties being sued by the parents of a young camera assistant who died during the production of &ldquo;Midnight Rider,&rdquo; a movie based on Allman&rsquo;s memoir.  The crew was struck by a freight train in southeast Georgia.</p>

<p>The parents of 27-year old Sarah Jones filed a lawsuit that names 10 individuals associated with the film.  Including Allman, director Randall Miller, his production company, as well as CSX railroad.</p>

<p>“They did so many wrong things on so many levels, it’s just unbelievable,” Richard Jones said. “This should not have happened. It’s senseless.”  The lawsuit accuses all parties of negligence and seeks unspecified monetary damages.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/songoftheday/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T11:49:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/songoftheday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://i1.ytimg.com/vi/soOfcwQ3J8A/maxresdefault.jpg" width="250" height="225" title="RS #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/soOfcwQ3J8A " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Summer Camp Music Festival today!</p>

<p>Song: Nebraska &ndash; Moe.</p>

<br />


<p>Send us your song of the day at <a href="&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#x67;&#114;&#x6f;&#111;&#x76;&#101;&#117;&#110;&#x69;&#111;&#x6e;&#64;&#x6f;&#x75;&#116;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#107;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;">&#x67;&#x72;&#111;&#111;&#x76;&#101;&#x75;&#110;&#x69;&#x6f;&#110;&#x40;&#111;&#117;&#x74;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#111;&#107;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x6d;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer Camp Music Festival: 2008 vs. 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/21/summercamp-music-festival-2008-vs-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-21T13:10:19-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/21/summercamp-music-festival-2008-vs-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://grooveunion.github.io/images/scamp14.jpg" width="190" height="225" title="scamp #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>As an avid festival goer for the past decade, I can say with confidence that Summer Camp Music Festival is the place to be this year. With its best lineup ever, latest daily band schedule with the main stages playing until 2AM, and longest band list to date, you do not want to miss it! Summer Camp Music Festival is a 3-day festival held every year over Memorial weekend in Chillicothe, IL (just outside of Peoria). Summer Camp began in 2001 with a bill of only 11 bands. In its 14th year, the festival will host more than 125 bands next month. Last week, Rolling Stone magazine even named Summer Camp as one of the “Summer 2014’s 40 Must-See Music Festivals”.</p>

<p>This writer has been to more than 10 different festivals across the county, and will be attending my 7th Summer Camp this year with my first having been in 2008. Instead of writing a post talking about how many amazing bands are going to be there and who they are, this post is intended to shed light on the changes that Summer Camp has made in the past 7 years to make this one of the premiere festivals in the country. Besides, a lineup including 3 nights of Moe., 3 nights of Umphrey’s Mcgee, 2 sets of Trey Anastasio Band, Primus, G. Love &amp; Special Sauce, Blues Traveler, The Wood Brothers, Yonder Mountain String Band, and Keller Williams should pretty much speak for itself in my humble opinion.</p>

<p>There have been so many positive changes to the festival since 2008 that the first or second-time Summer Camp goer would have no clue about! This is one of the only festivals in the country that listen to the feedback from people that attend the festival and actually make the desired changes. Don’t get me wrong, there are still some major changes in my opinion that would help the festival tremendously. However, the changes that have been made since 2008 have helped the festival in more ways than I could have hoped to imagine.</p>

<p>The biggest difference that has helped Summer Camp become more “user-friendly” is the set up at the festival entrance. My first year in 2008, we went on the Thursday for the Pre-Party and sat in line for at least 4-5 hours before even getting inside the festival (after we had already parked). It was one, giant line that wrapped all the way around into the parking lot. The security check, wristbands, late night tickets, EVERYTHING was all in ONE single line all while baking in the hot sun with fully loaded wagons, carts, arms, bags, backpacks, etc. It was a nightmare to say the least. By the time we got through the line, half the day was already over. Now, flash-forward to 2014. There’s a separate pod for your tickets before you get in the line, along with a handful of lanes at the security checkpoint instead of just one. It has saved hours upon hours of waiting time at the entrance and is so much more fluid.</p>

<p>The next big thing that helped was a very subtle change that most people probably thought was no big deal. For the first five years I attended Summer Camp, there was only one way in and one way out of the main stage at the festival off to the side (Moonshine). Last year, they created a big hole/path in the back of Moonshine Stage so that you can walk straight through the back which gives a direct line to the other main stage (Sunshine). And for people like me, this was huge because our campsite was between Moonshine and Sunshine right behind the Moonshine stage behind this newly created path.</p>

<p>The last major difference I’d like to bring up is one that rookie Summer Campers may have no clue about. The location of Sunshine stage has been in a new location the past two years in comparison to years past. The location of where Sunshine used to be is now more area for camping. They moved the stage further out in a parallel fashion to expand the boundaries of the festival which has helped tremendously for this growing festival. Moving the stage allowed for more people to attend the festival, it is not as cramped in the camping area, and it has created more standing room for the stages.</p>

<p>What am I most excited for this year at Summer Camp in my 7th year that will be different from the rest of the years I have attended? THE SCHEDULE! Two of the most heartbreaking things about Summer Camp in the past have been the main stages only playing until 10 or 11PM each year and how you have to have additional tickets for the late night shows in the red barn which always end up being headlining acts like Umphrey’s Mcgee and Moe. I will be going down a new path this year at Summer Camp by finally springing for VIP tickets. There are a lot of perks that make VIP worthwhile that I could get into, but possibly my favorite perk is my choice of one late night ticket in the red barn. I have tried the past 6 years to see a show in the barn, but only got lucky enough to get into only one show. This year, I have my late night ticket and am ready to go. As for the schedule, the main stages will be going until 2AM this year, which will make Summer Camp even better and I did not think that was possible.</p>

<p>Now if we can just get the folks that put on Summer Camp to pave the parking lots as well as keep all the torrential rain away that have dampened (literally) 3 of my last 6 Summer Camps, then this festival would be absolutely perfect. Don’t get me wrong, every time it has rained I have still had the time of my life. But, it did take my girlfriend some talking into for this year. It took me seven years, but this year I will be ready for the rain. I will be ready with my rain suit and men’s rain boots (yes that’s a real thing).</p>

<p>The GrooveUnion squad will all be in attendance next weekend for Summer Camp, and we will be reporting back to our readers about the best moments, sets, bands, and experiences that we have this year at the best festival on the planet! Stay tuned, and stay groovy.</p>

<p>LINK FOR SUMMERCAMP PAGE: <a href="http://summercampfestival.com/">http://summercampfestival.com/</a></p>

<p>Spotify Playlist: <a href="https://play.spotify.com/user/summercampfest/playlist/0Dg70qPImUry6QILrrm9Or">https://play.spotify.com/user/summercampfest/playlist/0Dg70qPImUry6QILrrm9Or</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/21/songoftheday/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-21T12:21:01-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/21/songoftheday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lz9xmbcQDN1qip5uuo1_400.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="RS #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/wRcVQDELAd4 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Song: Got to Give it Up &ndash; Marvin Gaye</p>

<br />


<p>Send us your song of the day at <a href="&#109;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#103;&#x72;&#x6f;&#111;&#118;&#x65;&#117;&#x6e;&#x69;&#111;&#x6e;&#x40;&#111;&#x75;&#x74;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#x6b;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;">&#x67;&#114;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#118;&#101;&#x75;&#x6e;&#105;&#111;&#110;&#64;&#111;&#117;&#116;&#108;&#x6f;&#111;&#x6b;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x6d;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paul McCartney Music Video]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/20/mccartneymusicvideo/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-20T00:59:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/20/mccartneymusicvideo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/news_landscape/2014/05/paul_mccartney_robot.jpg" width="250" height="180" title="Paul and Newman" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Today, Paul McCartney released his new video for <em>Appreciate</em> in support of his latest LP, <em>New</em>.  Guest starring in the video is Newman the Robot.</p>

<p>The video begins with Newman walking around an office before him and McCartney fall into an epic staredown.  McCartney breaks the silence and begins singing to Newman.  The rest of the video, Paul and Newman are dancing around, enjoying themselves like two peas in a pod.  That didn&rsquo;t take long for a friendship to come together.  Paul and Newman, Newman and Paul.  A match made in heaven.  watch the video below.</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/VpxdtWJAfSY " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SNL Dj Davvincii]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/19/snldjdavinici/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-19T23:32:46-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/19/snldjdavinici</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.vanyaland.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Andy-Samberg-DJ.png" width="305" height="185" title="sambergdj" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Here&rsquo;s Andy Samberg playing Dj Davvincii.</p>

<p>Wait for the drop.. Wait for it&hellip;&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/assets/4470643/tumblr_n5r0kgDNft1rdzuduo1_500.gif" width="350" height="350" title="djdav" ></p>

<p>(via The Verge): <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/5/18/5727788/snl-digital-shorts-return-with-davvincii-to-skewer-edm-and-overpaid-djs">http://www.theverge.com/2014/5/18/5727788/snl-digital-shorts-return-with-davvincii-to-skewer-edm-and-overpaid-djs</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/19/songoftheday5-19/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-19T21:49:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/19/songoftheday5-19</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://scentsofself.files.wordpress.com/2010/06/omf.jpg" width="270" height="225" title="RS #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>WHAM!!!!  What a great video.</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/pIgZ7gMze7A " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Even better video.</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/98AzJT8FlmY " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Song: Wake Me Up Before Ya Go-Go &ndash; Wham</p>

<br />


<p>Send us your song of the day at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#103;&#114;&#x6f;&#111;&#118;&#x65;&#117;&#110;&#x69;&#111;&#110;&#64;&#x6f;&#x75;&#116;&#x6c;&#111;&#x6f;&#107;&#x2e;&#x63;&#111;&#x6d;">&#103;&#114;&#x6f;&#111;&#118;&#101;&#x75;&#x6e;&#105;&#111;&#110;&#64;&#111;&#x75;&#x74;&#108;&#111;&#x6f;&#107;&#46;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x6d;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Smashing Pumpkins Album]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/18/smashingpumpkinsalbum/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-18T00:59:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/18/smashingpumpkinsalbum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.mtv.com/crop-images/2013/09/09/Smashing%20Pumpkins%20Official%20Site.jpg" width="250" height="225" title="SM #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>According to Tommy Lee, Billy Corgan is about to deliver “the best record he’s ever written.” Lee, who is drumming on Smashing Pumpkins’ forthcoming LP <em>Monuments To An Elegy</em>, spoke to Billboard about the recording process. He added, “These are like epic, goose-bump songs. It sounds like the first couple of Smashing Pumpkins records. I was fucking blown away.”</p>

<p>Corgan previously said he expects the album, along with a second Pumpkins LP called Day For Night, to be released in 2015. He described the albums’ sound by saying, “think: ‘guitars, guitars, guitars, and more guitars;’ but more so on the epic side of things than say, grossly metallic.”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Roots: Understand Music Video]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/18/understandmusicvideo/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-18T00:58:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/18/understandmusicvideo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.okayplayer.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Understand-still3.jpg" width="225" height="200" title="roots" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>The Roots have unveiled the music video for their latest single &ldquo;Understand&rdquo;.  The song is from the album titled &ldquo;And Then You Shoot Your Cousin, which is due out May 20th.  The video is an absolutely stunning stop motion clip that follows around several objects.  The video is intentionally trippy and pretty difficult to, dare I say it, understand?</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3WrDF5LQpNk " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Jackson Hologram]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/17/mjhologram/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-17T23:31:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/17/mjhologram</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://images.contactmusic.com/images/feature-images/michael-jackson-xscape-cover-slice-636-380.jpg" width="250" height="225" title="mj #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Michael Jackson is set to appear in hologram form at Sunday&rsquo;s Billboard Music Awards.  Billboard originally hinted at the holographic appearance when they promised a &ldquo;world premiere experience&rdquo; from Jackson.</p>

<p>Is there anything more disrespectful to Michael Jackson and his abilities, than to present him in hologram form?  I mean, we don&rsquo;t even know which Michael Jackson is going to show up.  Will it be the black moonwalking Jackson?  Will it be the white ghoulish figure that we saw from the Bad album and on?  Will it be baby Michael?  I for one vote for baby Michael.  That&rsquo;s the only Michael Jackson hologram I believe I could tolerate.  Little Michael up there singing and dancing, and still looking like a normal human being.  If any other Michael shows up it&rsquo;s all a sham.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/17/songoftheday5-17/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-17T21:49:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/17/songoftheday5-17</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://images.sodahead.com/polls/002193085/373495130_sublime_sun_xlarge.gif" width="200" height="225" title="sublime sun #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/eSte_c82p6U " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>Song: Summertime(Doin&#8217; Time) &ndash; Sublime</p>

<br />


<p>Send us your song of the day at <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#103;&#114;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#x76;&#x65;&#117;&#x6e;&#105;&#111;&#x6e;&#64;&#111;&#117;&#x74;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#x6b;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;">&#x67;&#114;&#111;&#x6f;&#118;&#101;&#117;&#110;&#105;&#111;&#x6e;&#x40;&#x6f;&#117;&#x74;&#x6c;&#x6f;&#x6f;&#107;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will Ferrel Chad Smith Drum Battle]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/17/drumbattle/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-17T00:59:09-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/17/drumbattle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.stadium-arcadium.com/images/chad-smith-will-ferrell-twins-look-a-like-comparison/chad-smith-will-ferrell-twins-look-a-like-comparison2.jpg" width="150" height="220" title="chad and will" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>One week from today, On May 22nd, the people will get what they want.  Red Hot Chili Peppers drummer Chad Smith and his look-a-like Will Ferrell will have a drum off on The Tonight Show starring Jimmy Fallon.</p>

<p>Last February, during a Reddit AMA Ferrell wrote &ldquo;A lot of people think that it&rsquo;s me playing for the Red Hot Chili Peppers.  But that would be an insult to Chad Smith.  The truth of the matter is there is no Will Ferrell.  Only Chad Smith.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Smith issued a challenge to Ferrell in response: &ldquo;Stop impersonating me.  In fact, I need you&hellip; drum battle.  Me and You.  I&rsquo;ve seen your skills; you don&rsquo;t got &lsquo;em.  Let&rsquo;s Go.  Golden cowbell. Winner. Boom!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Ferrell accepted the offer on the condition they raise $300,000 for the charities Cancer for College and Little Kids Rock, which has already been accomplished.</p>

<p>In a recent interview with Rolling Stone, Smith expressed confidence:  I&rsquo;m all for it.  But unless Will&rsquo;s been practicing or is secretly a crazy, wild drummer, I think it&rsquo;ll be evident right off the bat who the real Chad Smith is.  I&rsquo;m ready to take him down.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riot Fest Suprise]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/riotfest10albums/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-16T23:32:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/riotfest10albums</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.altpress.com/images/uploads/news/RiotFest-generalheader.jpg" width="250" height="200" title="riot2" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>To commemorate its 10th anniversary, Riot Fest has announced that 10 bands will perform classic albums in full at the festival.  Among the participating bands:</p>

<ul>
<li>Weezer (The Blue Album)</li>
<li>Janes Addiction (Nothing&rsquo;s shocking)</li>
<li>Descendents (Milo Goes to College)</li>
<li>The Get Up Kids (Something to Write Home About)</li>
<li>Slayer (Reign in Blood)</li>
<li>The Offspring ( Smash)</li>
<li>NOFX (Punk in Drublic)</li>
<li>Samhain (Initium)</li>
<li>Naked Raygun (Throb Throb)</li>
</ul>


<p>The 10th and final band to play an album in full is yet to be announced.  &ldquo;We have promised to unveil it in a separate announcement in the upcoming weeks, as well as additional 10th anniversary surprises.&rdquo;  Click &ldquo;here&rdquo; to see Riot Fest dates and schedule.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Page Fed Up With Plant]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/pagefedupwithplant/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-16T23:32:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/pagefedupwithplant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://i262.photobucket.com/albums/ii101/SteveAJones2008/1995_10_13PagePlantWilliamJMielenz.jpg" width="185" height="200" title="PagePlant" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Jimmy Page it seems, is just as annoyed at the lack of a Led Zeppelin reunion as the rest of us normies are.  In response to Robert Plant&rsquo;s comments a few weeks ago about not wanting to be &ldquo;part of a jukebox&rdquo;, Page said he feels Plant is just jerking the bands chains.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I was told last year that Robert Plant said he is doing nothing in 2014, and what do the other two guys think?  Well, he knows what the other guys think.  Everyone would love to play more concerts for the band.  He&rsquo;s just playing games, and I&rsquo;m fed up with it, to be honest with you.  I don&rsquo;t sing, so I can&rsquo;t do much about it.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Page then reiterated his desire to play live as Led Zeppelin again.  &ldquo;Absolutely, absolutely.  I definitely want to play live.  Because, you know, I&rsquo;ve still got a twinkle in my eye.  I can still play.  So, yeah, I&rsquo;ll just get myself into musical shape, just concentrating on the guitar.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Even though the Led Zeppelin reunion seems very unlikely, Page said he like to play with someone, somewhere in the near future.  &ldquo;I&rsquo;m not devoid of ideas.  So let&rsquo;s hope that some time in the next year, I&rsquo;m seen to be playing out there.  Because that&rsquo;s the only thing that&rsquo;s been missing.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Lately, Page has been focusing on upcoming reissues of Zeppelin&rsquo;s first three records.  &ldquo;This is a wealth of musical content and attitudes and variations,&rdquo; he stated.  &ldquo;That passing on of the baton, if you like, is part of the whole thing.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jack White New Single]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/jackwhitenewsong/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-16T23:31:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/jackwhitenewsong</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://i1.ytimg.com/vi/13cf6_MBwZM/0.jpg" width="200" height="200" title="Jw" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Jack White will return on June 10th with his solo album, <em>Lazaretto</em>.  We posted <em>Lazaretto</em> as our Song of the Day last week and now, White has released another track for the album.  The bluesy &ldquo;Just One Drink&rdquo; can be listened to below (via Rolling Stone)</p>

<p>In support of the release of the album, White will embark on a world tour beginning at the end of May.</p>

<p>Lazaretto Tracklist:</p>

<ol>
<li>Three Women</li>
<li>Lazaretto</li>
<li>Temporary Ground</li>
<li>Would You Fight For My Love?</li>
<li>High Ball Stepper</li>
<li>Just One Drink</li>
<li>Alone in my Home</li>
<li>Entitlement</li>
<li>The Black Bat Licorice</li>
<li>I think I Found The Culprit.</li>
<li>Want and Able</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FYF Fest Lineup]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/fsffestivallineup/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-16T23:31:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/16/fsffestivallineup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://37.media.tumblr.com/ef561c029a542fb6f11b8bf049cf69dd/tumblr_n5og8vvcDG1qffaooo1_500.jpg" width="185" height="200" title="fyf" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>FYF Fest has revealed its 2014 lineup.  The Los Angeles-based music festival will take place August 23rd-24th at LA Sports Arena and Exposition Park.  The Strokes and Phoenix will serve as the two headlining acts, with other notable acts including Interpol, Flying Lotus, Blood Brother, Julian Casablancas and many others.  Check out the full lineup here:  <a href="http://fyffest.com">http://fyffest.com</a></p>

<p>Tickets will be available Thursday, May 22nd at Noon PST via the festival&rsquo;s website, and two day general admission passes will cost $129.00.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
