<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></title>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-01T13:20:38-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Song of the Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/04/30/songoftheday4-slash-30-slash-14/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-30T21:49:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/04/30/songoftheday4-slash-30-slash-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.laterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/Screen-Shot-2013-11-22-at-9.11.50-AM-680x446.png" width="250" height="225" title="happy #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/y6Sxv-sUYtM " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>My first song of the day goes out to me! I&rsquo;m happy because I finally finished <a href="http://www.grooveunion.com">http://www.grooveunion.com</a> and have it live and functional.  Yet, I realize I still have a lot of work to do to perfect the website.  Just like the song, coding can get repetitive and tiresome.  But screw it because I&rsquo;m happy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trey Pistachio and The Phish]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/04/29/trey-pistachio-and-the-phish/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-29T16:03:18-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/04/29/trey-pistachio-and-the-phish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://bloximages.chicago2.vip.townnews.com/poststar.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/1/dd/1dda9f90-3b7b-11e3-937b-0019bb2963f4/52671a59411b1.preview-620.jpg" width="250" height="225" title="phish satire #1" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>POST: 6 days ago, ‘The National Report’ posted a story about the Mayor of Glens Falls, NY petitioning the City Council to rename the town after the band Phish. At first read, you may not pick up that the article is a complete work of satire. I personally did not pick up on the satire at first as I am an extremely gullible person. I just thought the writer was highly misinformed and did not fact check anything he was writing, as he got most of his information wrong. For example he was calling the band “The Phish” instead of Phish, naming the band member “Trey Pistachio” instead of Trey Anastasio, and even had the city spelled wrong as “Glenn Falls” instead of Glens Falls.</p>

<p>However, one reader took the story very seriously and took his opinion to a whole new level in the comments section. ‘Jerry Greene’ posted almost immediately after the story was published with the following: “My two teens attended a Phish concert last year and I’ll regret it for the rest of my life. My 15 year-old daughter came home high on LSD, and my 17 year-old boy has decided to turn gay. It’s simply an outrage that these druggie sodomites aren’t behind bars for life so they will be completely removed from our civilized society.“ Upon reading this, I had myself a nice long belly laugh at Mr. Greene’s comment.</p>

<p>I started to create an account with the site for the sole purpose of responding to Jerry’s comment pointing out how is he so wrong in so many ways. But, where do you even start with a person like this and would it do any good for someone that would be ridiculous enough to post something like that? Ultimately, I decided that Mr. Greene was not worth my time or effort. All I can say is I can only hope that Mr. Greene was responding to a satirical article with a satirical comment. We will leave it up to the reader to decide.</p>

<p><a href="http://nationalreport.net/mayor-rename-town-jamband-phish/">http://nationalreport.net/mayor-rename-town-jamband-phish/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
