<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Reviews | GrooveUnion]]></title>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/categories/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-11T15:03:28-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch: Jack White Live In Concert Webcast]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/06/11/jack-white-free-webcast-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-11T14:08:27-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/06/11/jack-white-free-webcast-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/white.jpg" width="230" height="225" title="White Webcast" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>On Monday night (June 9) Jack White celebrated the release of his latest solo album, <em>Lazaretto</em>, with a live concert and webcast from the historic Fonda Theater in Hollywood, Calif.  The show started out with White playing many songs from the new album and lead into a mix of old White Stripes classics.</p>

<p>Please, if you have the two and a half hours, click the link below and watch the full webcast of the show.  White was in an energetic and talkative mood.  The energy was on full blast all night, and the setlist was carefully crafted with mind numbing jams sparsed inbetween.  Even though I am occasionally put off by White&rsquo;s high pitched guitar style, it really sets the tone for the band and the crowds enthusiasm.  His solos are so well placed you habitually get lost in its psychedelic tendencies.</p>

<p>White is a songwriting genius who hasn&rsquo;t lost a step since his White Stripes days.  He seems to be having as much fun as ever and should be on every music fans bucket list.  His energy, stage presence, and originality are unmatched in the industry today.</p>

<p>P.S. What the hell is the instrument the lap steel guitar player is playing in the middle of the show?</p>

<p>Live Webcast link:  <a href="http://www.npr.org/event/music/319666614/live-tuesday-jack-white-in-concert">http://www.npr.org/event/music/319666614/live-tuesday-jack-white-in-concert</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
