<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Reviews | GrooveUnion]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/categories/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-23T17:32:51-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Avett Brothers Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/02/the-avett-bros-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T14:05:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/02/the-avett-bros-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/avettbros.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Avett_Brothers,_Pickathon_2006.jpg">Photo</a> by David Owen/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en">CC By 3.0</a>


<br/ >
<br/ >
<br/ >

The Avett Brothers
<br/ >
6/14/2014
<br/ >
The Lawn at White River State Park
<br/ >
Support: Langhorne Slim & the Law

</div>




<br/ >


<p>It is hard to find a more entertaining show out there than the Avett Brothers. Their stage presence is undeniable and has your heart racing from the first beat to the last beat. Whether they are stomping on the stage or hopping around, they will leave you wanting more. This was not the first time I have seen the Avett Brothers at White River, but I must say I enjoyed this year’s show compared to last time there three years ago. However, this was mostly due to the show being outdoors in the middle of October. I had trouble enjoying the show because I was struggling to keep myself warm the entire show.</p>

<p>This time around, I could not have asked for better weather. It was perfect outside, and they killed it with a twenty-four song set list. They started out strong with some well-known songs like ‘Live and Die’ and ‘Pretty Girl from Cedar Lane’ before settling down with songs like ‘Vanity’ and ‘Laundry Room’. Right after ‘Vanity’, they busted out my personal favorite ‘Kick Drum Heart’ which had the crowd back up and dancing after a few slow ones.</p>

<p>One thing I do remember about the show a few years ago were the uniquely chosen covers like Neutral Milk Hotel’s ‘In the Aeroplane Over the Sea’. No Neutral Milk Hotel this time, but they did however cover a pretty fun George Jones song called ‘The Race Is On’. I had not heard this one before, but I liked it. The same could be said about the first song of the encore which was a Doc Watson cover called ‘Little Sadie’.  They closed the show out with the crowd favorite and ever-popular ‘I and Love and You’. This was the same song they closed with last time I saw them, and I would not have had it any other way this time around. It is such a pretty melodic song with outstanding lyrics that had the whole crowd singing along.</p>

<p>I do not know the Avett Brothers catalog as well as a lot of other bands I listen to, but they always put on an incredible show. With unmatched energy and a style that hits a few different musical genres, they are able to keep the set lists fresh and exciting. This concert-goer will be 100% going back to see the Avett Brothers next time they are in Indiana.</p>

<p>SETLIST: <a href="http://www.setlist.fm/setlist/the-avett-brothers/2014/farm-bureau-insurance-lawn-at-white-river-state-park-indianapolis-in-6bc07e72.html">http://www.setlist.fm/setlist/the-avett-brothers/2014/farm-bureau-insurance-lawn-at-white-river-state-park-indianapolis-in-6bc07e72.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[John Butler Trio Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/02/john-butler-trio-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T12:13:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/08/02/john-butler-trio-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/JBT.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4f/Bonnaroo08_jackjohnson2_lg.jpg">Photo</a> by Nigel Cooke/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/deed.en">CC By 2.0</a>


<br/ >
<br/ >
<br/ >

John Butler Trio Review
<br/ >
6/12/2014
<br/ >
Egyptian Room at Old National Centre

</div>




<br/ >


<p>John Butler Trio has been hitting the road hard in support of their most recent album, Flesh &amp; Blood. The GrooveUnion crew and I caught their show at the Egyptian Room at Old National Centre in Indianapolis, and wow what an entertaining show. They played all the hits you could hope for with their new songs perfectly mixed in to the set.</p>

<p>Not to take away from the show, but I remember seeing him at the Egyptian Room in 2008 and his look and energy was definitely different in 2014. In 2008, he was hopping and dancing around the stage the entire time like you see Michael Franti do at his shows. Also in 2008 John had long dreads, baggy hippy pants, and a hippy t-shirt. Flash forward to 2014, John was a little different. He was dressed very nice with a clean-cut, perm-like hair-cut. Not to mention, he stayed somewhat stationary the entire show not really dancing and hopping around. When I noticed the changes as he came on stage and started playing, I was a little reserved as to how the show would unfold in comparison to 2008. John put all those worries to rest quickly with his unbelievable show. This show was just as good, if not better, than the show in 2008.</p>

<p>The band started out nice and calm with their new song ‘Cold Wind’, before ripping into old songs ‘Revolution’ and ‘Used to Get High’ and they never looked back! You could feel the vibe of the crowd intensifying as they killed it with ‘Used to Get High’. There was everyone from teenagers to senior citizens getting down and dancing through the set.  There was one specific senior citizen lady that seemed to be one of his biggest fans close to us that was dancing like a teenager the entire show. It was very entertaining for us throughout the show.</p>

<p>As the band continued through their nineteen song set, they continued to place new songs in like ‘Bullet Girl’, ‘Only One’, ‘Blame It On Me’, ‘Devil Woman’, ‘How You Sleep at Night’, and ‘Livin’ in the City’. All in all, they played 7 of the 11 new tracks from Flesh &amp; Blood and I was not upset. Usually when I see a band touring in support of a new album, I always am hoping they will stick to their old songs. With the new Flesh &amp; Blood, that was not the case with John Butler. I love the new CD, and loved hearing them live.</p>

<p>For the GrooveUnion crew and I, there was one song that we were all hoping for in the back of our heads and is obviously ‘Ocean’. After about half of the set was complete, John was on stage alone and busted into ‘Ocean’ and it is just utterly amazing. I have been to a countless number of concerts, and hearing ‘Ocean’ live by John Butler is still hard to beat. It is one of the most awe-struck moments you could ever have at a concert. It just puts you in a trance from the first note to the last note and he could not have played it any more perfect.</p>

<p>John Butler Trio is one of those shows that is pretty much impossible not to leave in a better mood than when you arrived. He is such a happy, uplifting performer that I would see again and again. It is amazing that he still makes stops in places like Indianapolis all the way from Australia while still playing all his hits for his fans that we know and love. One thing is for sure John, you are always welcome back and we will be there when you come.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch: Jack White Live In Concert Webcast]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/11/jack-white-free-webcast-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-11T14:08:27-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/11/jack-white-free-webcast-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/white.jpg" width="220" height="225" title="White Webcast" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>On Monday night (June 9) Jack White celebrated the release of his latest solo album, <em>Lazaretto</em>, with a live concert and webcast from the historic Fonda Theater in Hollywood, Calif.  The show started out with White playing many songs from the new album and lead into a mix of old White Stripes classics.</p>

<p>Please, if you have the two and a half hours, click the link below and watch the full webcast of the show.  White was in an energetic and talkative mood.  The energy was on full blast all night, and the setlist was carefully crafted with mind numbing jams sparsed inbetween.  Even though I am occasionally put off by White&rsquo;s high pitched guitar style, it really sets the tone for the band and the crowds enthusiasm.  His solos are so well placed you habitually get lost in its psychedelic tendencies.</p>

<p>White is a songwriting genius who hasn&rsquo;t lost a step since his White Stripes days.  He seems to be having as much fun as ever and should be on every music fans bucket list.  His energy, stage presence, and originality are unmatched in the industry today.</p>

<p>P.S. What the hell is the instrument the lap steel guitar player is playing in the middle of the show?</p>

<p>Live Webcast link:  <a href="http://www.npr.org/event/music/319666614/live-tuesday-jack-white-in-concert">http://www.npr.org/event/music/319666614/live-tuesday-jack-white-in-concert</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jack Johnson Concert Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/06/jackjohnsonreview/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-06T13:34:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.grooveunion.com/blog/2014/06/06/jackjohnsonreview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/jackjohnson.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4f/Bonnaroo08_jackjohnson2_lg.jpg">Photo</a> by Josh Rhinehart/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en">CC By 3.0</a>


<br/ >
<br/ >
<br/ >

JACK JOHNSON CONCERT REVIEW
<br/ >
6/1/2014 The Lawn at White River State Park
<br/ >
Support: Amos Lee

</div>




<br/ >


<p>Anybody that lives in Indiana knows that you never know what the weather could be like at any given hour at a time. Last night, the Jack Johnson concert on the Lawn at White River State Park proved this point even further. Yesterday started as a beautiful day only for the weathermen to announce late in the day that severe weather was coming and was going to hit hard until about 8:45PM. The opener, Amos Lee, came on and played about three songs before they kicked him off the stage and urged everyone to exit the venue and seek shelter at approximately 7:45. It was barely drizzling and partly cloudy with a handful of lightning bolts. However, the masses started the mass exodus to neighboring buildings to catch a few drinks before heading back to the Lawn and catch Jack’s set which the venue stated they were sure would still happen.</p>

<p>Well, the rain never came and everyone started pouring back into the venue about 20-30 minutes after the announcement was made telling everyone to leave. It never did end up raining, ended up feeling perfect outside, and Jack still played an entire two-hour set beginning at 9PM that covered everything from his first album to his newest album along with some excellent covers.</p>

<p>I have seen Jack multiple times, and every time I get worried Jack is going to stick to new material during his set and steer away from his older hits that made me fall in love with Jack originally. This was definitely not the case. He had a perfect balance of old hits, new hits, and covers nicely placed throughout the set. It also was amazing that his band supporting him was members of ALO (Animal Liberation Orchestra), who is also a band on the same label as Jack. They added an extra something to the show that would not have been the same without them.</p>

<p>Most people get the impression that a Jack Johnson show would be a boring, quiet show that is not very upbeat. Jack kept the crowd into it the entire time and was even listening and playing requests that were screamed out from the crowd! Not only that, he even played a song the crowd was screaming for all night that was actually an ALO song. It is nice when a popular musician like Jack can put his ego aside and give the fans what they want, and Jack was definitely showing this side of him to his fans last night and you could tell the crowd loved it.</p>

<p>It was a bummer to a lot of Amos Lee fans in attendance that his set got cut short. However, Jack made right by bringing him and his band on stage multiple times to play with him along with 2 or 3 songs in the encore. To end the show, Jack had the members from ALO, Amos Lee and his band, and himself on stage to close the set. There were a lot of people on stage at that moment, but it was amazing how fluent and great they all sounded together like they had been doing it for years!</p>

<p>A Jack Johnson concert is never going to be the best concert you have ever seen, nor will it ever be the worst concert you have ever seen. But it has always entertained me in a big way and I leave happy and satisfied every time. Jack has never changed his musical style unlike many artists today, and he should be commended for that. I saw Jack about 8 years ago, again about 4 years ago, and now last night. It has gotten better and better each time, and I will continue to go see him as long as he continues to tour!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
