<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Review | GrooveUnion]]></title>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/categories/review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-11T14:49:19-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jack Johnson Concert Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/06/06/jackjohnsonreview/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-06T13:34:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/06/06/jackjohnsonreview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/jackjohnson.jpg" width="200" height="225" title="bottle smash" ></p>

<!--more-->




<div style="text-align:center" markdown="1">
<a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4f/Bonnaroo08_jackjohnson2_lg.jpg">Photo</a> by Josh Rhinehart/ <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en">CC By 3.0</a>


<br/ >
<br/ >
<br/ >

JACK JOHNSON CONCERT REVIEW
<br/ >
6/1/2014 The Lawn at White River State Park
<br/ >
Support: Amos Lee

</div>




<br/ >


<p>Anybody that lives in Indiana knows that you never know what the weather could be like at any given hour at a time. Last night, the Jack Johnson concert on the Lawn at White River State Park proved this point even further. Yesterday started as a beautiful day only for the weathermen to announce late in the day that severe weather was coming and was going to hit hard until about 8:45PM. The opener, Amos Lee, came on and played about three songs before they kicked him off the stage and urged everyone to exit the venue and seek shelter at approximately 7:45. It was barely drizzling and partly cloudy with a handful of lightning bolts. However, the masses started the mass exodus to neighboring buildings to catch a few drinks before heading back to the Lawn and catch Jack’s set which the venue stated they were sure would still happen.</p>

<p>Well, the rain never came and everyone started pouring back into the venue about 20-30 minutes after the announcement was made telling everyone to leave. It never did end up raining, ended up feeling perfect outside, and Jack still played an entire two-hour set beginning at 9PM that covered everything from his first album to his newest album along with some excellent covers.</p>

<p>I have seen Jack multiple times, and every time I get worried Jack is going to stick to new material during his set and steer away from his older hits that made me fall in love with Jack originally. This was definitely not the case. He had a perfect balance of old hits, new hits, and covers nicely placed throughout the set. It also was amazing that his band supporting him was members of ALO (Animal Liberation Orchestra), who is also a band on the same label as Jack. They added an extra something to the show that would not have been the same without them.</p>

<p>Most people get the impression that a Jack Johnson show would be a boring, quiet show that is not very upbeat. Jack kept the crowd into it the entire time and was even listening and playing requests that were screamed out from the crowd! Not only that, he even played a song the crowd was screaming for all night that was actually an ALO song. It is nice when a popular musician like Jack can put his ego aside and give the fans what they want, and Jack was definitely showing this side of him to his fans last night and you could tell the crowd loved it.</p>

<p>It was a bummer to a lot of Amos Lee fans in attendance that his set got cut short. However, Jack made right by bringing him and his band on stage multiple times to play with him along with 2 or 3 songs in the encore. To end the show, Jack had the members from ALO, Amos Lee and his band, and himself on stage to close the set. There were a lot of people on stage at that moment, but it was amazing how fluent and great they all sounded together like they had been doing it for years!</p>

<p>A Jack Johnson concert is never going to be the best concert you have ever seen, nor will it ever be the worst concert you have ever seen. But it has always entertained me in a big way and I leave happy and satisfied every time. Jack has never changed his musical style unlike many artists today, and he should be commended for that. I saw Jack about 8 years ago, again about 4 years ago, and now last night. It has gotten better and better each time, and I will continue to go see him as long as he continues to tour!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
