<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: News | GrooveUnion]]></title>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-15T12:23:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[GrooveUnion]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Justin Timberlake's Michael Jackson Tribute]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/jttributesmj/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-14T12:36:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/jttributesmj</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://www.soultv.com.mx/es/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/justin-jackson-160x145.jpg">http://www.soultv.com.mx/es/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/justin-jackson-160x145.jpg</a>" width="125" height="300" title="JTMJ" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/oG08ukJPtR8 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>

<p>This is pretty cool.  I always enjoy a good Michael tribute.  There&rsquo;s just something about Michael Jackson&rsquo;s voice that puts you in a good mood.  Especially when it&rsquo;s set to a random person and little kid montage.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metallica Acoustic?]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/metallicaacoustic/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-13T16:13:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/metallicaacoustic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://www.livemetallica.com//images/shows/071027_01.jpg">http://www.livemetallica.com//images/shows/071027_01.jpg</a>" width="250" height="205" title="metallica" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Last night in Los Angeles at the 10th anniversary MusiCares MAP Fund benefit concert for addiction treatment, Metallica performed an acoustic set in honor of Ozzy Osbourne.  Osbourne was being celebrated with the Stevie Ray Vaughan Award for his commitment to helping people who have struggled with addiction.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not really sure which one is more odd: Metallica doing an acoustic set or Metallica doing an acoustic set in honor of Ozzy Osbourne?  It just&hellip;. doesn&rsquo;t seem to fit.</p>

<p>The award was presented to Osbourne by Eagles guitarist Joe walsh, who called Osbourne &ldquo;the grandfather of heavy metal.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Osbourne&rsquo;s band closed out the night and began its performance with &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know,&rdquo; with Dave Navarro playing guitar.  Ozzie being Ozzie, he decided the crowd wasn&rsquo;t lively enough.  &ldquo;You could look like you&rsquo;re having a bit more fun,&rdquo; he joked as he tossed a bucket of cold water into the crowd.  I mean there weren&rsquo;t any bats around to bite the head off of so a bucket of cold water to the crowd was going to have to suffice.  &ldquo;Was I really so bad all these years that they&rsquo;re giving me an award for being sober?&rdquo; Yes Ozzie, yes you were.</p>

<p>Slash joined Osbourne on stage for the final song &ldquo;Paranoid,&rdquo; but Osbourne was still not happy with the crowd telling them: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t get too crazy.  You might enjoy yourselves.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Maybe the crowd just had no clue what he was saying the entire time.</p>

<p>The MusiCares MAP Fund provides members of the music community access to addiction recovery treatment regardless of their financial situation.  It also offers support groups and sober living resources for working members.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bob Dylan Plans New Album]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/newbobdylanalbum/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-13T15:39:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/13/newbobdylanalbum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://www.uncut.co.uk/sites/default/files/imagecache/article/2013/11/bobdylan020712w00010.jpg">http://www.uncut.co.uk/sites/default/files/imagecache/article/2013/11/bobdylan020712w00010.jpg</a>" width="250" height="205" title="dylan" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Recently, Bob Dylan posted a new cover of Frank Sinatra&rsquo;s &ldquo;Full Moon and Empty Arms&rdquo; on his website.  The song is expected to be part of a forthcoming album due later on this year.</p>

<p>There is no confirmed album title, however, on Dylan&rsquo;s homepage there is an image of Dylan with the phrase &ldquo;Shadows in the Night&rdquo;.  The image is without a doubt a hint at a possible album cover and title.</p>

<p>The music fan in me is excited about the possibilities of yet another Dylan album.   However, the cynic in me can only hope that Bob Dylan can somehow use modern technology to shadow his ever fading voice and musical spirit.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.bobdylan.com/us/node/31389">http://www.bobdylan.com/us/node/31389</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jay Z attacked]]></title>
    <link href="http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/12/jayandsolange/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-12T20:09:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grooveunion.github.io/blog/2014/05/12/jayandsolange</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right <a" src="href="http://cdn.images.express.co.uk/img/dynamic/79/590x/solange-475497.jpg">http://cdn.images.express.co.uk/img/dynamic/79/590x/solange-475497.jpg</a>" width="250" height="225" title="Jay z" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>I can&rsquo;t say I don&rsquo;t enjoy seeing Jay Z getting assaulted.  Anybody with that much influence and power needs to be beaten down a few notches usually.  I also enjoy seeing his security guards half heartedly protect him against the attempted beatdown.  Especially when everyone starts to walk out of the elevator and they just leave them two behind to duke it out some more.  Yea I get they were trying to act normal for the crowd, but thats breaking up fights 101.  You don&rsquo;t leave the two high school kids in the same room after a fight.  &ldquo;Here kids sit down next to each other and we&rsquo;ll figure out what to do with you in the other room.&rdquo;  Of course in a few minutes they&rsquo;ll be beating the shit out of each other again.</p>

<p>She&rsquo;s probably pissed she got such a shitty end of the stick with the Knowles family.  She doesn&rsquo;t have the looks, her names Solange, and she doesn&rsquo;t get to sit courtside at Nets games.</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rWdhX9c_7FA " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
